They say you shouldn't do that.
我勸你還是別那樣做
Huh?
什麼？
Blowing on it. It doesn't help.
就是吹氣啊，那是沒有意義的
I saw it on Yahoo! Chiebukuro.
Yahoo奇摩知識上面有寫
It's got Umaibo crumbs in it too.
而且你把美味棒的碎屑都吹進去了
Hey, it works.
喂，明明就能用嘛
Well? Did you put it on?
怎麼樣？穿好了嗎？
Cute.
真可愛
That's nice, too.
這件也很棒
Looks good on you.
好合適喔
Pretty.
太漂亮了
Yay.
耶
Perfect.
完美極了
I don't know which one to pick.
怎麼辦？好難抉擇喔
Nagisa, what's your budget?
渚小姐，預算大概是多少？
By the way,
話說回來
doesn't your hair feel a bit heavy?
你不覺得頭髮很沉重嗎？
How about a trim?
去剪一下吧
What?
什麼？
But you already got me a bunch of clothes.
可是已經讓你買那麼多東西了
It's fine.
不用在意
I want you to look even cuter, Junko.
我想讓純子變得更加可愛
Let's go!
我們走吧
Hello.
你們好
Sorry about our sudden visit, Naoki.
不好意思突然過來，直樹
This is the girl.
要剪頭髮的就是她
You're cute.
你好可愛
I'm Naoki, I'll cut your hair.
我是今天的設計師，直樹
Junko, I'll be working remotely from the cafe across the street.
那待會見囉，純子 我到對面的咖啡廳遠距工作
Okay.
好
Thank you.
麻煩你了
What style should we go for?
要剪成什麼樣子呢？
Do you have any particular style that you like, Junko?
純子，你有喜歡的髮型嗎？
Um…
我想想…
You can decide.
交給你決定吧
I saw the article about the drama.
連續劇的報導出來了呢
Yeah. I'll share my screen with you.
是啊，我現在分享畫面
KENTARO EMO RETURNS TO DRAMA AFTER 16 YEARS
（江面賢太郎睽違16年的新作！）
SEVENTEEN: I WON'T FORGET THIS SIGHT A REIWA LOVE STORY
（《17歲，永不忘卻這景象》 令和的純愛故事）
"Glad I waited."
“等待是值得的”
"This is so emotional."
“太感動了”
"A school drama by Emoken! So pumped for this one."
“是江賢寫的！ 而且是校園劇，期待得不得了”
So far, the comments are all positive.
目前留言板上都是正向的留言呢
That's why I'm worried.
所以才令人擔心啊
Anti-fans are bound to pop up eventually.
接下來恐怕也會出現一些黑粉
If Mr. Emo ever egosurfs, he's going to hit a roadblock again.
要是江面先生自我搜尋 肯定又會停筆的
Anti-fans? Egosurf?
“黑粉”？“自我搜尋”？
What was the name of the quiz show you were on the other day, Mr. Ogawa?
小川先生上次參加的 問答節目叫什麼來著？
General Knowledge Quiz?
《常識問答》？
General Knowledge Quiz. Search the hashtag.
你試著用主題標籤搜尋《常識問答》
That's egosurfing.
那就叫做自我搜尋
#GENERAL_KNOWLEDGE_QUIZ
（#常識問答）
"This shortie, Ogawa or something, sucks."
“這個叫小川的矮子糟透了”
"So loud and annoying."
“大吼大叫地吵死人了，無法接受”
"He's like some PE teacher. LOL."
“自以為體育老師嗎？www”
"Screw off, Ogawa."
“小川消失吧”
"Go to hell, Ogawa."
“去死吧，小川”
Shut up, you idiots!
少囉嗦啦，蠢貨！
What do you know, anyway? What do you…
你根本不了解我，你又懂什麼…
Damn it!
該死！
Who the hell are you? Come fight me!
你是什麼人啊？給我出來啊！
Am I a PE teacher? The hell I am!
“自以為體育老師嗎？” 我就是啦！
Those are the side effects of egosurfing and dealing with anti-fans.
那就是自我搜尋與黑粉引發的副作用
That's scary. Egosurfing is scary.
好可怕，自我搜尋太恐怖了
When's the deadline for the script of the first episode again?
第一集的劇本截稿日是何時？
Friday.
星期五
But he hasn't finished writing the script yet, has he?
不過他絕對還沒開始寫吧？
Huh? Why are you asking me?
幹嘛？為什麼要問我？
Huh?!
啥？
The influencer, 19 years his junior, posted this picture.
小他19歲的網紅上傳照片了
-Seventeen!
-《17歲》！
Let's order some wine.
來杯葡萄酒吧
A lighter red this time.
這次來淡一點的
What? Aren't you going to get writing?
什麼？編劇老師不是該寫劇本嗎？
Don't you need to write?
你不寫沒關係嗎？
Typing on the keyboard isn't the only time I'm writing.
不是只有敲鍵盤的時候才叫“創作”
Just like waiting for wine to open up,
像這樣等待葡萄酒 味道產生變化的時刻
even in the time waiting for my ideas to ripen,
等待好點子成熟的這段時間
I'm already in the process of writing.
對我來說都是在創作
Deep!
好深奧喔
Minami, compared to your photos, you seem a bit…
小南，你看起來比照片上
chubbier.
還要豐腴一些呢
It's coming to me.
靈感來了
A 17-year-old girl…
17歲的少女…
-Take notes. -Right.
-快記下來… -是
That's when he went home, but did he fail to write?
他說完就回去了，結果還是沒寫嗎？
Maybe he really is old news.
那個人是不是已經過氣了啊
Huh?
不會吧？
Is that Junko?
純子？
You look great.
很不錯耶
What should I do?
怎麼辦？
I got asked out on a date.
他邀我去約會了
What?!
什麼？
The Skytree…
我提到說
I mentioned wanting to go up there,
想去晴空塔上面看看
and he said he'd take me there after he gets off work at 6 p.m.
他就說六點下班後，可以帶我去
Way to go.
你很行嘛
What do you mean, a date? Hey! Answer me!
你要去約會？純子 喂，快點回答我！
-I'll cover for you with your dad. -Don't ignore me! Hey!
-我會應付你父親 -別不理我啊！喂！
You should go.
你就好好去玩吧
Appreciate it.
麻煩你了
I'll try to get back before it's too late.
我會盡快回來的
Wait, you hussy!
給我等一下，不要臉的女人！
Sex five seconds after meeting?
跟男人見面五秒就要合體了嗎？
Have fun…
路上小心
Mom.
媽媽
Hey!
喂！
Where did my Junko go?
我的純子去哪了？
Mutchy,
學長
didn't we agree she's my Junko?
不是說好純子是我的嗎？
Kiyoshi!
阿清！
Don't you ever let her go.
不准你再放開她的手
You got that?
聽懂了沒？
That was then, this is now.
那時候只是順勢講出來了
Where is she?
純子去哪了？
Answer me!
回答我！
PAY WITH E-MONEY
（電子支付請在此感應）
Huh? Bleep.
什麼？嗶
We're so high up!
好高啊！
The cars look so tiny!
車子變得好小！
This really is your first time.
你真的是第一次來啊
Yeah.
對
I live way out in the boonies.
我家在非常鄉下的地方
Only one bus runs once a week.
一星期只有一班公車
For real?
這麼少？
Huh? What is it?
等等，怎麼了？
What's the matter?
你是怎麼了？
Where's the time machine?
時光機在什麼地方？
What?
什麼啊？
Junko!
純子！
Hey!
喂！
It's me, Mutchy!
是我，阿睦！
You told him?
你告訴他了？
-Where are you? -Sorry.
-你去哪了？ -抱歉
How dare you lie to me!
你竟然敢欺騙我！
Saying Junko is dying
一下說純子會死
and has turned into a frog.
一下說什麼她是青蛙，要我保持距離
No, I said frogification phenomenon.
不是青蛙，我是說蛙化現象
Shut up, you time traveler!
少囉嗦，未來人！
Now that I take a closer look,
仔細一看，你們這對母子
you and your son have faces that scream future.
確實長得很有未來感
Damn it!
可惡！
You think I'm dumb because I'm a punk who only finished junior high.
看我是學歷只有國中的混混 就這樣耍我
Junko!
純子！
Can you hear me?
你聽見了嗎？
Why do you buy what he said so easily?
為何會這麼輕易就相信啦？
Because without a time machine,
因為如果沒有時光機的話
Doraemon wouldn't have been able to meet Nobita.
哆啦A夢就無法與大雄相遇了啊
I wish I could've taken photos of that view.
我真想把那景色拍成相片
I never thought things would unfold like this.
沒想到會有這樣的發展
What's happening tomorrow?
明天呢？
I might stay over at Naoki's place.
可能會去直樹家過夜
-No!
-絕對不行！ -為什麼啊？
I didn't bring you here for hanky-panky, you ugly!
我不是帶你來這裡亂搞的，醜女！
A male hairdresser?
明明是個男人，當什麼美髮師？
I'm sure he's a good-for-nothing flirt.
肯定不是好東西，吊兒郎當的
I agree, Father.
我同意，爸
A black suit at a disco is much more grounded than him.
迪斯可的黑衣領班都還比他踏實 而且還有員工宿舍！
Look.
這樣拍
See?
你看
You can see the picture without developing it.
就算不洗出來，也能看到相片喔
What is this thing?
這是什麼呀？
Take it down a notch, Junko.
適可而止啊，純子
Sorry. I woke Machato up.
抱歉，我把阿正吵醒了
Hey.
嘿…
Just to clarify,
我只是想確認一下
have you told her that she's marrying you?
你會跟純子結婚這件事…
I haven't. And I won't.
我沒說，也不會說
Then don't mention "black suit" or refer to him as "Father."
那就別再說什麼 “迪斯可黑衣領班”跟“爸”這種話
Stop dropping hints.
是怎樣？刻意暗示？
My bad.
抱歉
But seeing my wife's face
但是看到太太的臉
triggers a flood of memories.
就讓我想起很多事情
Will you stop? It's putting Mom off.
別這樣，媽媽都被你嚇到了
She's not your mom and she's not your wife.
她不是你媽媽，也不是你太太
She's my daughter!
是我的女兒
Right.
知道了
But instead,
相對地，爸
allow me to sleep with Junko tonight--
我今晚可以跟純子一起睡…
Absolutely not!
當然不行！
I mean, we're a married couple.
但我們是夫妻耶
I have a feeling I can finally perform tonight.
我覺得今晚久違地有幹勁了
How dare you! I'll kill you!
在說什麼鬼話？小心我宰了你
There, there.
好乖喔…
Machato is so cute.
阿正好可愛喔
I can't wait to have a kid, too.
我也好想快點生個小寶寶
He's your grandson.
他是你孫子啦
It's not exactly…
說是回歸原點…
a return to my roots.
又有點不太一樣
I just happened to be in the mood
碰巧我現在有種心情
to create a story about teenagers.
想編織一個關於青少年的故事
He talks a lot despite not writing anything.
明明就沒在寫，還真敢說呢
He loves interviews.
他最喜歡接受採訪了
He's the epitome of craving recognition.
他極度渴望被人認同
The epitome of what?
認同什麼？
He wants to be acknowledged, praised, pampered, and flattered.
希望大家認同他、稱讚他 慰勞他、要大家吹捧他
Egosurfing?
自我搜尋？
I never do that.
我不做那種事
I don't write for a million people whose faces or names I don't know.
我不是為了那些 不知長相和姓名的一百萬人
Instead,
而是為那獨一無二的
I write
孤獨之人
for one lonely person.
而在寫作
Emiko…
其實惠美子…
is the daughter of Director Takagi, who passed five years ago.
是五年前過世的高木專務的親生女兒
This is a drama airing on another TV station.
這是其他電視台正在播出的連續劇
And these are real-time comments from viewers.
然後這是觀眾的即時實況
-"Finally!" -"It's coming together."
-“來了！第一集的伏筆！” -“伏筆收得真好！”
This is scary.
等等，好可怕啊
One person at a time!
一個一個來！
I'm not Prince Shotoku!
我可不是聖德太子！
These days, viewers share their predictions as they watch.
最近的觀眾在觀看節目時 會研究劇情發展並留言討論
They're not watching, are they?
他們根本就沒仔細看吧？
They're a crucial audience,
不過他們是很重要的觀眾
and their desire for recognition is fulfilled like this.
而且這些人都是在這裡 滿足被認同的慾望
We got caught in the crossfire.
出現了，是流彈
"Does Emoken still have what it takes to deliver foreshadowing to this extent?"
“我不確定現在的江賢 是否能把伏筆收得這麼好”
That's nasty. Isn't it?
真討厭啊，是吧？
What's the matter, Hamura?
怎麼了？羽村
Mr. Emo just updated his social media.
江面先生剛才更新社群網站了
"I wonder if the deadline can be extended by a week, meow."
“截稿日可以往後延一星期喵？”
It's the foreshadowing, you see.
那個伏筆實在是…
I'm not sure if I can pay off
我不確定第一集的伏筆
the first episode's foreshadowing in the finale.
能不能在最後漂亮收尾
Did you egosurf?
你自我搜尋了吧？
I didn't.
我沒有
If we postpone by a week, the preparations will also be set back.
要是延後一週 所有準備工作都會延遲啊
What kind of foreshadowing is this?
到底是怎樣的伏筆？
You're writing for one lonely person, right?
你是為了獨一無二的 孤獨之人所寫的吧？
I might not look like it, but I'm quite lonely. So, tell me.
別看我這樣 其實我挺孤獨的，說給我聽聽吧
A 17-year-old girl.
年齡17歲
-She is from the boonies. -It's delicious.
-從鄉下來的女高中生… -真好吃
-And a young content writer… -Good.
-跟年輕的網路作家… -那就好
-They fall in love. -Let's swap.
-會墜入愛河 -交換吃吧
But the girl
但是這名少女
harbors a secret.
藏有一個祕密
And the two are fated never to be.
兩人注定不能終成眷屬
It's already carved in stone.
這是一開始就決定好的
A secret?
什麼祕密？
In Roman Holiday,
如果是《羅馬假期》的話
the girl's secret was that she was a crown princess.
那少女的祕密就是 她其實是王位繼承人
But nowadays…
然而現在這時代…
It's tough to come up with obstacles for love in this era of diversity.
要想出阻礙戀情的點子很不容易 畢竟這是講求多樣化的時代
Why not make her ugly?
不能因為是她很醜嗎？
Like that would work!
廢話，當然不行
Give her a time limit, then.
那來日不多如何？
A time limit?
來日不多？
This ugly girl doesn't have long to live.
就是那個醜女活不了多久了
-The date of her death is already set. -Why?
-她的死期已定 -為什麼？
You're the professionals. Think of something.
你們可是專家，也一起想想啊
It could be an accident or a sickness.
不論是遭遇事故也好，生病也行
Too flimsy.
太膚淺了
It's deep.
好深奧
And the girl knows--
這件事女生自己知道…
No, the guy should learn about it first.
不，男方先知道比較好
It's the theory of tragedy.
就悲劇的理論來說
The man grapples with conflict after learning the girl's secret.
男方得知少女的祕密後 內心產生的糾葛
I can write this.
我倒寫得出來
This time, I can write.
這次我寫得出來
BUS TIMETABLE
（公車時刻表）
It says 3:55 p.m.
“3點55分”
That's when the time machine arrives.
那是時光機到達的時間
We hid it so present-day people wouldn't uncover
這是我們未來人
the secret of us future people.
為了不讓現代人發現 而隱藏起來的祕密
If I get on this bus, I better be able to go.
搭上這班車，真的能到達吧？
What?
怎樣啦？
I didn't draw them.
我沒畫
Okay, I did.
好啦，我有畫
I don't want to be looked down on in the future.
這是為了不在未來被人瞧不起
I promise to bring Junko back.
我一定會把純子帶回來的
So long.
再見啦
BOUND FOR KODAI SEIMON-MAE
（往工大正門前）
Mr. Yasumori.
安森老師
Hey.
你們好
I am now…
我現在啊
in the future.
正身處未來
This…
這一步…
is one small step for Mutchy.
對阿睦來說是小小的一步
But one giant leap for…
但是對人類來說…
I wonder why Midori Satsuki is so sexy.
五月綠為什麼會那麼性感啊？
I'm still in junior high, so I wouldn't know.
-我還是國中生，所以不懂啦 -我想也是
This is totally Showa.
這肯定是昭和
They tricked me!
我被騙了啦！
Tsuyoshi Sako's mother thanked me.
佐高強同學的母親向我道謝
She said she asked her son
聽說她問了兒子
why he only hung out with Kiyoshi.
為什麼只跟阿清做朋友
Her son said,
她兒子回答說
"I had a few friends who visited before,
雖然至今為止有好幾位朋友來找他
but Kiyoshi was the first one who didn't tell me to attend school."
但阿清是第一個沒叫他回去上學的人
I see.
這樣啊
And I informed Kiyoshi about this.
我轉告了阿清這件事
He doesn't have to come to school.
就算他不來學校
Because I can hang out with him at his place.
只要我去他家，就能一起玩啊
I see.
是喔
Kiyoshi understands.
他能夠理解
It's tough to hear "Come to school" when you already know you have to.
心裡知道自己該去學校
He took time off too.
他也曾是不就學的孩子
But there are things you can only learn in a school setting.
但是有些事情 只有透過校園生活才能學習到
Mr. Yasumori.
安森老師…
It's not just about studying.
除了學習之外
You should have shared memories from field trips and sports events.
若是沒有校外教學 運動會等共同的回憶
-Otherwise, when you-- -Mr. Yasumori.
-等他出了社會… -老師
Are you married?
你結婚了嗎？
Not yet.
還沒
What about it?
這有什麼問題嗎？
Would you say the same if your own son refused to go to school?
若換作是你的孩子不上學 你也會這樣說嗎？
I would.
當然會啊
I would make him go to school, no matter what.
無論如何我都會讓他去上學
He'd stab you if you're not careful.
弄不好的話，他有可能會刺傷你喔
That's ridiculous.
怎麼可能
What?
怎樣啦？
You clearly got upset just there.
你剛才明顯露出不快的神情了吧？
Because I mentioned marriage when you're already feeling pressured to.
因為你心裡知道自己該結婚了 卻被人說中痛處
Excuse me.
我先失陪了
Wait a minute.
請等一下
It's true, I'm a conservative teacher.
我確實比較保守
I'm narrow-minded and unable to crack a single joke.
連個基本的玩笑都不會講
I'm boring and unpopular.
是一點也不有趣的惹人厭教師
I didn't go that far.
我沒說得那麼過分
Let go of me.
放開我
However,
但是呢
despite my looks,
儘管我有這長相
Mr. Ogawa surpasses me in popularity, and I can't fathom why.
人氣卻遠遠不及小川老師 我實在是無法理解
I'm the homeroom teacher, while he's just an assistant.
為何大家不喜歡我這班導師 偏偏喜歡副班導的小川老師？
I'm eight heads tall, while he's only five heads--
不是喜歡八頭身的我 而是五頭身的小川老師…
Stop right there.
等一下
I never mentioned Mr. Ogawa.
我剛才完全沒提到小川老師啊
You're dating him, right?
你們在交往吧？
Absolutely not!
並沒有！
You're not?
原來沒有啊？
Next song, the ninth place for this week…
接下來是本週的第九名
I love you.
我喜歡你
You've got to be kidding.
你在開玩笑吧？
Crap, I said it.
怎麼辦？我說出口了
Don't turn it up.
真的假的？別調高音量
Lower it.
弄小聲點…
This must be a joke.
不會吧
Sorry, I'm singing in Japanese.
不好意思，我用日語唱哦
Wow.
好酷喔
I didn't recognize any of the songs you sang.
你唱的歌我全都沒聽過
Sorry.
抱歉呀
I don't know the latest tunes.
我不曉得最近的新歌
No worries.
這樣很好啊
It's new for me.
反而很新奇
I'm hitting the bathroom.
我去一下洗手間
STUDENT ID SHOWA 61
（學生手冊 昭和61年）
BORN SHOWA 43
（出生於昭和43年）
Showa 43?
“昭和43年”？
CAN YOU EXPLAIN THIS?
（這是怎麼回事？）
SORRY
（對不起）
YOU MIGHT NOT BELIEVE ME
（你可能不會相信）
BUT SHE'S MY MOM
（那女孩是我的母親）
What?
什麼？
I'LL EXPLAIN EVERYTHING LATER.
（我之後會好好向你解釋的）
"I'll explain everything later."
“我之後會好好向你解釋的”
How did it go?
結果如何？
I had such a great time.
我玩得超開心的
-I snapped a bunch. -Photos?
-我拍了好多 -照片嗎？
Let me see.
讓我看看
Everyone is so nice to me.
大家都對我很溫柔呢
I wonder why.
是為什麼呢？
Because you're cute.
因為你很可愛啊
Stop it. It messes with my groove.
別說了，會讓我不知所措
It puts me more at ease to be called ugly, like my dad does.
大家要是像老爸那樣叫我“醜女” 感覺還比較自在
When I first met your dad, he called me ugly too.
我第一次遇見你爸的時候 也被他罵“醜女”呢
He likes you, Nagisa.
他很喜歡渚小姐
Mr. Ogawa?
你說小川先生嗎？
I'm not sure.
是這樣嗎？
It's true.
是啊
What about you?
渚小姐呢？
How do you feel
你對老爸
about my dad?
有什麼想法？
I like him.
很喜歡喔
Really?
真的嗎？
That's a relief.
那太好了
Unless he finds happiness,
他要是不過得幸福
I can't become independent either.
我也沒辦法離開他獨立
He might have a sharp tongue, but he's not stupid.
雖然講話難聽，但是並不笨喔
So please…
還請你多關照
take care of Ichiro Ogawa.
小川市郎就交給你了唷
Sure. Goodnight.
好啦，晚安
Goodnight.
晚安
Have you noticed any health changes like dizziness or fever since your return?
你回來後身體有出現什麼變化嗎？
Barkeep, a pizza toast.
老闆，來塊披薩吐司
I want a pizza toast.
我要披薩吐司
"Not me"?
“我是沒有”？
Actually, I brought my daughter along.
其實我女兒也跟我在一起
What?! You've brought Junko?
搞什麼？純子學姐也來了？
You can't just do that.
你怎麼可以擅自這樣做？
I'll send her back on Saturday.
星期六我就會送她回去啦
And your wife, or should I say, ex-wife?
還有你的老婆，應該說是前妻？
She's on the PTA board.
她當上家長會的幹部了
Speaking of which,
說到這個
just how long does Sakae plan to stay there?
紗加惠她到底打算 在那邊待到什麼時候啊？
Enjoy.
請慢用
Eiji Bando?
板東英二？
Yes.
沒錯
I've decided to think of you as Eiji Bando.
我決定把你想成是板東英二
I'm a little confused.
我聽不太懂耶
First, the looks are exactly my type.
首先，外表完全正中我的喜好
You mean Eiji Bando?
板東英二嗎？
I mean you.
我是說你啦
Use your head a little.
稍微想一下就知道了吧
Right. Sorry.
你說得對，抱歉
You shouldn't judge someone
不可以用外表
By their looks
來判斷一個人
But your looks are exactly her type
但外貌是我喜歡的那一型
I'm against lookism
反對外貌協會
What matters is what's on the inside
最重要的是內涵
But inside he's conservative
但他的內在太保守
And yet, his looks are exactly my type
然而臉蛋卻正中紅心
Because of your looks, I find myself going easy on you.
都是因為你那帥氣外表 害我在評分時會放水
That's not fair.
這樣不公正
So until I find something positive about you beyond your looks…
所以在我找到 你除了外貌以外的優點前
Bang bang bang
磅…
You're Eiji Bando
你就是板東英二
You used to play for the Chunichi Dragons
你是前中日龍隊的
Bang bang bang
磅…
Eiji Bando
板東英二
Lookism and Dragons
外貌協會和中日龍隊
I'm wavering between those two
在這之間搖擺不定的我
Bang bang bang
磅…
Is that your answer to my question?
那就是你給我的答覆嗎？
Answer?
答覆？
Well,
這個嘛
I suppose so.
算是吧
What on earth?
這是什麼？
"Emoken announces retirement."
“江賢斷筆宣言！
"Steps down from drama after 16 years."
睽違16年的連續劇決定不寫了
"Press conference on Friday."
週五召開記者會？”
I was so shocked,
我真的嚇壞了
I accidentally used my pajama pants as a scarf.
本來是想披絲巾，結果披成睡褲
Sheesh.
真是的
What day is it?
今天是？
It's Friday!
星期五！
Forget the press conference, today's the deadline!
是記者會？才怪呢，截稿日！
Where is Mr. Emo?
江面先生是去哪了？
He's been in a Sheraton Hotel suite for the past four days.
他從四天前就窩在 喜來登飯店的套房裡
-Say what?!
-你說什麼？
You egosurfed, didn't you?
你自我搜尋了？
-I didn't. -You're lying!
-我沒有 -少騙人了！
You totally did!
你絕對有做！
Yesterday, I shared a concept video with the media.
昨天向媒體發布形象影片
In the spring of 2024,
2024年春天
in a corner of the city,
在都市的一隅
a 17-year-old girl crosses paths with a novice writer,
一名17歲的少女與新人作家相遇
and they spend the night together.
共度一夜
What is it?
怎麼了？
I'll take a photo.
我幫你拍吧
I want one together.
我想跟你一起拍
-Okay. Here we go. -However…
-好，要拍囉 -然而…
-Say cheese. Yay. -The girl has a secret.
-笑一個，耶 -這位少女有一個祕密
Get ready for an unpredictable and fresh love story.
是一部無法預測的全新愛情故事
Anyway, scroll down the article
然後從報導往下滑
and you'll find the comments.
底下就是留言板
"Must be a sickness."
“我猜是生病吧”
"I bet she doesn't have long to live."
“還剩下幾年可活的那種？”
They already guessed it.
一下子就被猜中了
That's what you get for egosurfing. You come across unnecessary stuff.
誰叫你要自我搜尋 特地跑去看那些不必看的留言
You don't know that until you see them!
該不該看，沒看過怎麼會知道！
At least show us what you've written so far.
至少把你已經寫好的部分給我看吧
We've come this far believing in you.
我們一路上都信任著你
We deserve this much!
至少有這個權利吧！
Let us read what you've written so far.
請你把已經完成的部分拿出來給我看
Don't pretend you've written a lot.
不用假裝你寫了很多
Just this?
就這麼一點？
I should've stepped down a little sooner.
我應該更早辭掉編劇職位的
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
That was fun.
好開心啊
Best of luck with your work.
你工作加油喔
I've taken tomorrow off, so how about a trip to Enoshima?
明天我請假了，要不要去江之島？
Tomorrow…
明天啊…
is Saturday, so I don't think so.
明天是星期六，我沒辦法
What?
什麼？
I need to head back soon.
我差不多該回去了
Having this much fun might jinx things.
玩得太開心會有報應的
By bus?
搭公車嗎？
By bus.
搭公車
Does that mean
意思是我們
we won't see each other again?
再也見不到面了嗎？
Probably.
也許吧
Why don't we go now?
那我們現在去如何？
To Enoshima?
去江之島嗎？
I want to show you all the sights I know.
我想帶你去能看到美景的所有地方
Let's go.
我們走吧
I should've admitted that I'm old now
我應該早點承認自己的衰老
and left sooner.
把機會讓出來
But you know,
可是啊
it makes me happy when I create something good,
要是能寫出好作品，我會很開心
and I was looking forward to the drama airing.
我也期待連續劇上映
Just getting by on past accomplishments
總是仰賴過去的成就來糊口
doesn't make me feel alive.
一點都沒有活著的感覺
Why is this so interesting?
為何會如此有趣？
Huh?
什麼？
I could've left if it was boring.
要是無趣的話我就能打道回府了
But these five pages
但是這五頁
are incredible!
未免也太出色了吧！
Right?
對吧？
Exactly.
正是如此
You get it.
你很懂嘛
Did you write it?
其實是你在寫？
No, um,
不是的，那個…
I just typed it out.
我只是重新輸入進去而已
Wait a minute, Mr. Emo,
難道說江面先生
you can't use a computer?
你不會用電腦嗎？
I'm embarrassed to say
說來慚愧
I'm not tech-savvy.
我超不擅長用數位產品
Amazing.
不得了
It's like I'm following your train of thought.
就像是在追蹤江面先生的思考迴路
How can you decipher them?
你看得懂？
-Mr. Emo. -Yeah?
-江面先生 -什麼事？
I'll pitch in ideas too, so let's finish the script today.
我也會提出一些想法 我們今天一起完成它吧
-What? -Huh?
-什麼？ -啥？
Are you serious?
你是認真的嗎？
I mean,
因為…
you struggled so much just to write five pages.
就為了這五頁，你卻重寫了好幾次
After seeing that, I can't help but lend you a hand.
我都看到了，怎麼能不幫你一把
In that case, um…
這樣的話，我想想…
Here it is.
就是這個
THIS SIGHT
（這景象）
It's about "this sight."
關於這個“景象”
If I were to feature it in the finale,
如果這在最後一集要讓觀眾看到
what should it be?
會是什麼樣的景色呢？
It might be cliché,
雖然會顯得老掉牙
but how about the sinking sunset?
夕陽西沉之類的？
Or an aquarium.
或是水族館
Or a shrine on a hill.
高地上的神社
Can I pay with e-money?
可以用電子支付嗎？
Sorry, we only take cash.
抱歉，我們只收現金
What?
什麼？
What's your first choice university?
你的第一志願決定了嗎？
Aoyama, I think.
應該是青山吧
MAY I GET INTO AOYAMA UNIVERSITY
（希望能考上青山大學）
Something feels off.
總覺得怪怪的
I think you're missing "Gakuin."
應該是“青山學院”吧
Right.
對喔…
AOYAMA GAKUIN UNIVERSITY
（青山學院大學）
What about Rome?
羅馬如何？
During the press conference,
公主在記者會上
when the princess is asked which city she enjoyed the most,
被問到“印象最深的地方是哪裡？”
Audrey Hepburn looks at Gregory Peck
奧黛麗赫本看著葛雷哥萊畢克的臉
and says, "Rome."
回答了“羅馬”
What?
不會吧？
Have you never seen Roman Holiday?
你沒有看過《羅馬假期》？
Nope.
沒有耶
These few years,
這幾年我只看 阿寅的作品和《卡車野郎》
Truck…
卡車…
That's no help at all!
太不像話了吧！
Let's just go with Rome, then. Hamura, can't we film in Italy?
算了啦，就羅馬吧 羽村，我們不能去義大利出外景嗎？
No.
當然不能
I'm no expert,
雖然我這外行人不是很懂
but if all this brainstorming isn't leading anywhere,
既然你想那麼久還是想不出來
maybe you should finish the first episode in a way that satisfies you.
或許你該先寫出能讓你滿意的第一集
I agree.
我也同意
I'm not writing for folks who'll just watch one episode and bail.
我才不要去迎合 只看第一集就棄追的跟風觀眾
This is Kentaro Emo's final work before retirement.
這可是江面賢太郎的退休作品耶
It needs a flawless four-part structure.
得有完美的起承轉合
Every foreshadowing in all the episodes must be resolved in the finale.
從第一集開始埋下的伏筆 要在最後一集全部漂亮收回
And the final piece falls into place in the last scene just before "The End."
在最終幕拼上最後一塊拼圖 然後打上“全劇終”
It's the only way.
只有這條路可走
Do they have to be resolved?
不得不收回來？
They do.
對
I'm a perfectionist.
我是完美主義者
It's always been my approach.
一直都是這樣走過來的
When you have a goal, the path becomes clear.
只要先決定終點，過程就會浮現出來
Then, writing the rest becomes easy.
然後我就能一口氣寫完作品
Do you think you're a god?
你以為自己是神嗎？
When it comes to my dramas, yes.
在我創作的連續劇中 我是這麼認為的
I have the perspective of a god.
我擁有上帝視角
No offense, but I think that's arrogant.
抱歉，但我覺得那只是傲慢
You don't know what happens
就是不知道結果如何
or how long something will last. That's what makes it intriguing.
不知道會延續到什麼時候 所以才有趣不是嗎？
You can't write unless you know the finale?
因為最後一集還沒定案就寫不出來？
Give me a break!
開什麼玩笑啊？
The…
我…
The finale for Junko and me
我跟純子人生的最後一集
is already set!
早就已經決定好了！
I win!
我贏了！
Not fair!
你太狡猾了啦！
Wait!
等一下啦！
Sorry.
對不起
I didn't mean to yell like that.
我說了自以為是的話
But…
但是…
everything has its end.
總有一天會結束
Even dramas and people's lives.
無論是連續劇，還是人生都是如此
So…
所以啊
up until the very last moment,
直到最後一刻來臨
why can't things be messy?
就讓劇情散亂一點也不錯嘛
The last episode is undecided?
最後一集竟然還沒確定
That's awesome!
那不是很棒嗎？
From my viewpoint, it's fantastic.
對我來說，那真是再好不過了
Excuse me.
不好意思
Hello?
喂？
What?!
什麼？
Sorry.
對不起
It's past 10 p.m., but she still hasn't come home.
都過十點了，她卻還沒回來
Yeah. Naoki.
對，直樹
She's with him, but…
直樹跟她在一起
Look.
你看
Yes.
太好了
We finally found it!
我們終於找到了！
She's with some dude? Damn it!
她跟男生在一起嗎？可惡！
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
My daughter
我女兒她…
might be having hanky-panky!
可能在做那檔子事！
You ordered way too much.
你點太多了啦
It's the last call.
可以最後加點
Aren't you going to drink alcohol?
你不喝酒嗎？
Well then, this wine, please.
那就這瓶葡萄酒
Right.
好的
What about you, Junko?
純子呢？
I'll have a little.
我也喝一點
DRINKING IS ILLEGAL UNDER THE AGE OF 20
（法律上未滿20歲禁止飲酒）
-Let's dig in!
-我開動囉
I've always wanted to do those typical teenage things.
我一直想試試看這種有青春感的事
Running on the sandy shore in the middle of the night,
像是半夜在沙灘上奔跑
absurd stuff like that.
然後玩得很瘋
Do you have a girlfriend, Naoki?
直樹有女朋友嗎？
Right.
這樣啊
It's not something you bring up unless asked.
沒問的話，本來就不會刻意提起嘛
Sorry.
抱歉
Don't be.
沒關係
I'm not single myself.
我也有男朋友
What's he like?
他是怎麼樣的人？
One of them…
其中一個人
is an older local punk.
是我老家那的流氓學長
There's another?
不只有一個人啊？
The other is a junior high kid who's all about boobs.
另一個是喜歡胸部的國中生
Yikes.
那很不妙吧
But
不過呢
they're both nice.
他們兩個都是好人
Stupid but nice.
雖然是笨蛋，但人很好
I see.
這樣啊
Everyone seems to be nice to me.
大家都對我很溫柔
Even my dad isn't nagging as much.
老爸最近也不囉嗦了
Nagisa too.
渚小姐也對我很好
I wonder why.
這是為什麼呢？
It's not like I'm a good girl or anything.
我根本就不是個好女孩呀
You're a good girl, Junko.
你是個好女孩，純子
A photo.
照片
Allow me.
我幫你拍吧
Make sure to get all the food.
料理也要全部拍進去
Sure.
好
Ready?
要拍囉
Say cheese.
來，笑一個
Here.
還你
I'll take one too.
我也來拍吧
A good girl wouldn't be out playing around this late.
如果我是個好女孩 就不會在外面玩到這麼晚了
What's wrong?
怎麼了嗎？
No, it's okay.
不，沒事
Huh?
奇怪？
I'm screwed.
完蛋了
What's the matter?
什麼？怎麼了？
I've lost my phone.
我的手機不見了
Huh?
真的嗎？
Excuse me.
打擾了
Here's your wine.
為兩位上葡萄酒
Please settle your bill first.
麻煩請先結帳
Don't you have your wallet?
你沒帶錢包嗎？
I do, but…
有是有…
Earlier,
但剛才…
I got that ema.
把錢拿去買繪馬了
Right, you were using that thing to pay for everything.
對喔，你全都是 用那玩意兒嗶一下付款
Junko,
純子
do you happen to have any cash?
你有帶錢嗎？
Sorry, I only have enough for my train ride home.
抱歉，我身上只有回去的電車錢
I'm screwed.
死定了
Huh?
什麼？
Can't you borrow money from someone?
沒人可以借錢嗎？
Like a coworker, your girlfriend, or your parents?
同事、女朋友或是雙親之類的
I could,
雖然有啦
but I don't know their numbers.
但我不知道他們的電話號碼
Right, it's all in that thing.
對喔，你全都記在那東西裡面
I even forgot my parents' number.
我連老家的電話都忘記了
I'm screwed.
完蛋了
So you're in trouble without that thing.
沒有那東西會完蛋啊
I told you to keep an eye on her.
我說過要好好盯著她吧？
Sorry.
對不起
She used to be back by 9 p.m. until yesterday.
到昨天為止，她都有在九點回家
You ogled her, didn't you?
你都用下流的眼神看她對吧？
This is on you!
都是你害的啦！
How can you say that when I have such innocent eyes?
怎麼會呢？我的眼神如此清澈
I hope she hasn't gone to Kabukicho or somewhere.
希望她沒有跑去歌舞伎町之類的地方
They say To-yoko is a rough place.
畢竟東橫那條街治安不太好
Toyoko? You mean Norengai?
東橫？是指暖簾街嗎？
There's a spot where runaway girls tend to gather.
那邊有個逃家少女的聚集地
What are you doing here, Inoue?
你為何在這啊？井上
Junko.
純子學姐…
Huh?
什麼？
What's that?
怎麼回事？
What's that noise?
這是什麼聲音？
A phone ringing?
電話響了？
Hello?
喂？
This is the Shonan police station in Kanagawa.
這裡是神奈川縣湘南警察局
SHONAN POLICE STATION
（湘南警察局）
Junko!
純子！
What on earth did you do?!
你到底在幹什麼啊？
Dining and dashing.
她吃霸王餐
When an employee tried to stop her, she turned violent.
店員想抓人時她極力反抗
Ow!
好痛…
-This is the police. -It hurts! Customer!
-我是警察，接到通報 -很痛耶，小姐！
-What are you doing?! -It hurts!
-等等，你在幹什麼啊？ -好痛！
-Ow! -Stop it.
-給我住手
No! Let go of me!
不是你想的那樣！放開我！
Let me go, pig!
放開我，臭警察！
I'll crush your balls!
小心我捏爆你的蛋！
Hey!
喂！
How shameful. You hussy!
丟臉死了，你這不要臉的女人！
-It's my fault. -Huh?
-是我的錯 -什麼？
This is Naoki, the hairdresser.
他是美髮師的直樹
Why aren't you locked up?
為什麼你沒有在牢裡？
He was sorry and came with us quietly.
因為他已經反省過，並積極配合我們
Is that so?
是這樣嗎？
My bad.
對不起
I dropped my phone, and I couldn't pay the bill.
因為我弄丟手機，導致無法付錢
You dropped your phone, huh?
只是弄丟手機而已嗎？
That's all that happened?
就只是弄丟手機而已吧？
Did you have hanky-panky with her?
沒有做那檔子事吧？
Not yet.
還沒做啦
If you'll excuse me.
那我就先告辭了
"Not yet"?
“還沒”？
Hold on.
等一下
You're seriously leaving now?
你真的打算在這時離開？
Yeah. Her father is here.
是的，她父親也已經到場了
How much do you know about Junko?
你對純子的事情了解多少？
How much?
了解多少？
She's a girl
她是一個會唱很多老歌的女孩
Is that all?
就這樣嗎？
Yeah.
是啊
You like her, don't you?
你喜歡她吧？
Don't you want to know more?
不會想了解更多嗎？
Stop it, Mr. Ogawa.
別說了，小川先生
If this were a drama, it's like you only tuned in midway.
如果比喻成連續劇 你就像是只看了其中的一集而已
If you enjoy it, wouldn't you want to watch the entire series from the top?
喜歡的話通常都會 想從第一集開始認真看到底吧？
Actually, I've never watched a series all the way through.
我不曾從頭到尾完整看過整部連續劇
-What? -I turn on the TV.
-你說什麼？ -打開電視的時候碰巧看到
And I watch the sixth or seventh episode.
就只看第六集、第七集
And if I enjoy that episode,
如果我覺得那一集很好看
then I'm a fan of that drama.
對我來說，那就是我喜歡的連續劇
Wait, what are we talking about?
等等，這是在說什麼啊？
Well…
那個…
You can leave. Sorry about that.
你可以先回去了，抱歉
Sorry, Junko.
對不起，純子
I was caught up with stuff and didn't pay attention to you.
爸爸太忙了，沒時間陪你
Did you have fun?
你玩得開心嗎？
Loads of fun.
非常開心
Thanks for not paying attention to me.
謝謝你沒空陪我
I've gotten the script.
我確實收下劇本了
Thank you.
謝啦
Crap.
可惡
What is it?
怎樣啦？
You seem a little different.
總覺得你變了
Not really.
沒有啊
I just took two weeks off from school.
只是兩星期沒去學校而已
Well then,
好了
I guess I'll head home soon.
我差不多該回去了
Right.
對了
Sako, here's a souvenir for you.
佐高，這是給你的伴手禮
What's that?
這是什麼？
"Mayonnaise Shrimp"?
“美乃滋蝦仁”？
What is it? I've never seen it before.
這是什麼口味？我第一次看到
What's the plan back home?
你回家要做什麼？
Studying.
讀書
I've decided to be a good girl.
我決定當個好孩子
Hey.
我問你喔
Which place in the future left the strongest impression on you?
在未來令你印象 最深刻的地方是哪裡？
What?
這個嘛…
I don't know.
是哪裡呢？
NO PHOTOS
（無照片）
They're gone.
全都消失了啊
Everything okay?
怎麼了嗎？
Let's see…
我想想…
The Skytree and Enoshima were both pretty,
雖然晴空塔和江之島都很漂亮
but my favorite place was…
但最棒的地方…
Junko!
純子！
Jail…
應該是…
I guess.
拘留所吧
Good work.
辛苦了
My phone was safe and sound.
我的手機安然無恙
Say hi to your mother.
請幫我向你母親問好
Cute.
真可愛
SEVENTEEN: I WON'T FORGET THIS SIGHT
（《17歲，永不忘卻這景象》 即將上映）
I am now…
我現在啊
in the future.
正身處未來
This…
這一步…
is one small step for Mutchy.
對阿睦來說是小小的一步
But one giant leap for…
但是對人類來說…
Huh?
什麼？
-Huh?
-不會吧！
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：盧慧文
Hold on.
等一下
It was just one mistake.
就只是犯錯一次耶
Don't defend someone who had an affair.
難道要替外遇的人說話嗎？
I really do have to resign.
我是不是只能辭職？
I don't think you guys have the right to judge.
你們應該沒有審判的權利吧？
Doppelganger.
分身
Like a tall rabbit.
-感覺是高大的兔子 -我也要加油
Patio!
中庭！
Straight out of Kintsuma.
像是《星期五的妻子》